Register of the Boris Michailovich Dulja Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Boris Michailovich Dulja papers,
1918-1942
2001C16
Dulja, Boris Michailovich, 1892-
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, writings, correspondence, and personal documents, relating to the Russian Civil War, and to Russian émigré affairs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biographical Note
1892 July 25 Born, Ekaterinodar, Russia
1927 Graduated, Vysoka Skola Zemedelska, Brno, Czechoslovakia
1933 M.S., Chemistry, Cornell University
Scope and Content Note
B. M. Dulja was a Cossack and an agricultural chemist. Of particular interest in this collection are his diaries of the Taman' operation in 1920, and reminiscences of student life at Cornell University (WRITINGS/"Vospominaniia"). The scrapbook in the biographical file contains military service records, identity papers and other matter relating to his life and career.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russians--United States.; Russia.; Soviet Union.; United States.
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1918-1942. (Box 1)
  Curriculum vitae, educational records, letters of recommendation, notebook, scrapbook and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Diaries, 1920. (Box 1)
  Account of Dulja's involvement in Gen. P. N. Vrangel's 1920 amphibious operation on the Taman' peninsula
- Correspondence, 1923-1942. (Box 1)
  Letters and postcards, arranged alphabetically by correspondent
- Writings, 1933 and undated. (Box 1)
  Article, memoirs and thesis, arranged chronologically by title
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1918-1942 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitae (Folder 1: 1)
  - Educational records., See also Scrapbook (Folder 1: 2)
    Includes correspondence with Cornell University and fellowship application.
  - Letters of recommendation for Dulja (Folder 1: 3)
  - Notebook (Folder 1: 4)
  - Scrapbook. (Folder 1: 5)
    Includes photographs, documents relating to Dulja's military service and education, as well as correspondence
  - Miscellany (Folder 1: 6)
- DIARIES, 1920. (Folder 1: 7)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1923-1942., See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Scrapbook
  - General, 1931-1940 and undated (Folder 1: 8)
  - Unidentified
    - General, 1923-1942 (Folder 1: 9)
    - Relatives, 1923-1933 (Folder 1: 10-11)
  - Buivid, Z. F., 1933-1942 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Bush, Milton T., 1934-1935 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Iavich (Yavitch), Mr., 1934-1937 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Nikulin, Ivan, 1934 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Kolachov, Paul, 1940 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Perepletchikov, Iu., 1933-1940 and undated (Folder 1: 17)
- WRITINGS, 1933 and undated
  - "Istoriia vozzrenii na pitanie rastenii i vitamin B1 v ego agrikul'turnom primenenii," n.d. (Folder 1: 18)
    Printed copy
  - "Vospominaniia o prokhozhdenii kursa Kornel'skogo universiteta," n.d. (Folder 1: 19)
    Holograph
  - "Some Contributions to the Quantitative Determination of Small Quantities of Iodine," M.S. thesis, 1933. (Folder 1: 20)
    Typescript